Owen Adrian

Software developer with 13 years of experience designing and developing applications and 7 years delivering web solutions with Ruby on Rails. Dynamic, creative, and entrepreneurial problem solver focusing on product-driven development.

Mesa, AZ · (816) 944-0745 · me@owen.codes · owen.codes

Technical Skills

- Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, C#, Python, HTML/CSS, Bash
- Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, ASP.NET, MVC, React, Svelte, Express.js
- Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- Cloud Platforms: Azure (App Service, Kubernetes), AWS (EC2, S3)
- Tools: Git, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD

Experience

Software Engineer Syntreno

Aug 2023 - Present

 Coordinated with non-technical leads to tailor an AI product for emulating standardized patients and exercising soft skills.

Software Engineer, Web

Unity Technologies

Mar 2021 - Jun 2023

- Implemented SSO and data providers in a React app, enabling PMs to import and manipulate third-party annotations from Autodesk, Procore, and Jira.
- Built RESTful APIs with ASP.NET for data annotation and importation.
- Developed a data streaming protocol that reduced buffer times by minutes.
- Containerized a monolithic application for deployment by the US Army Corps of Engineers and to aid in the reconstruction of Tyndall Air Force Base.

Senior Web Developer

VisualLive

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

- Maintained Ruby on Rails codebase and managed resources on Azure.
- Provided subject-matter expertise and developed custom CRM (Bitrix24, Salesforce) integrations for clients and marketing and sales teams.
- Sped up job runtime by 90% and cut costs by 15% with microservices.

Web Developer, Founder

Order Coffee Online

Sep 2017 - Mar 2020

- Developed an online ordering system with Ruby on Rails that processed over \$500,000 in sales from 3 cafes and made the mornings of over 3,000 customers.
- Led every stage of SDLC from conceptualization to commercialization, refined project goals with product feedback, and developed marketing strategies.

Education

Technology Solutions	Northland Career and Professional Studies	May 2018
High School Diploma	Liberty North High School	May 2018